AUTOPSY ROOM 3
(ツメ)牙通牙！
Fang Over Fang!
(キバ)母ちゃん 上だ！
Ma, above you!
わかってる。
I know!
死体を
盾にしやがったか…。
He used the corpse as a shield.
フンッ やっぱりだね。
I figured as much.
コイツは情報どおり 物理攻撃を
相手にするのは苦手のようだわ。
The reports were right.
Physical attacks seem
to be his weakness!
ヘッ！ だったら 俺たち
犬塚一族にとっては➡
Then we, the Inuzuka clan,
couldn't have asked for
a better opponent!
有利な相手だな。
母ちゃん！ 一気に片づけるぜ！
Ma, let's put him away in one stroke!
待ちな キバ。 コイツは あの自来也様を
倒した６人のうちの１人だ。
Hold it, Kiba!
He is one of the six who
brought down Lord Jiraiya.
ここは慎重に かつ 大胆に。
We're going to be cautious, yet bold.
子犬たちの護衛に向かった
ハナの分まで働いてもらうからね。
I expect you to fill in for Hana who
has gone to protect the puppies!
オ オウ…。
R-Right!
シノ 全力で駆除するぞ。
Shino, we’re going to exterminate her
with our full power.
(シノ)ああ。
Yes.
(テンテン)も～ お腹減った！
TEA HOUSE
I'm so hungry!
少し休んでいこうよ。
任務で疲れてるんだしさ。
Let's rest a bit.
We’re all tired from the mission.
(リー)どうなさったんですか？
ガイ先生。
What's the matter, Guy Sensei?
(ガイ)さっきから
鳥たちが やけに➡
Have you noticed large numbers
of birds
里側から飛んできてるとは
思わないか？
have been flying away from
the direction of the village?
それも逃げるようにな。
As though they were fleeing.
(ネジ)俺も イヤな胸騒ぎがする。
I also have this bad feeling…
ここは まっすぐ
里へ向かったほうがいい。
We should head straight
for the village.
(テンテン)え～！
What?!
(ガイ)行くぞ！ みんな！
Let's go, everyone!
んっ もう！
Aw geez!
後ろ！
Behind you!
鼻に六つ。 耳に七つのピアス…。
コイツか！
Six piercings in the nose,
seven in the ear… It’s him.
(綱手)お前は！
You’re…
お久しぶりです 綱手様。
It's been a long time, Lady Tsunade.
三忍も 今や あなただけだ。
You are the last remaining
of the Legendary Sannin.
少し アナタと話がしたい。
I wish to take a moment
to speak with you.
Pain to the World
Kiba! We'll go with that technique!
キバ あれでいくよ。
Yeah… I know!
ああ わかってる。
いくぜ 赤丸。
Let's do it, Akamaru!
ワン！
Dynamic Marking!
ダイナミックマーキング！
You won't get away!
逃がすか！
(カツユ)ここは もう大丈夫です。
I have control of the situation.
私が この２人を。
I will take care of these two.
Got it, thanks!
(キバ)ああ 頼んだぜ。
《赤丸のマーキングがついている以上➡
As long as you have
Akamaru’s marking,
there’s no place for you to escape!
どこにも逃げきれねえぜ》
This isn't Pain.
(シノ)コイツはペインじゃない。
Because her characteristics differ
from what we’ve been informed about.
なぜなら➡
我々が聞いた特徴と違っている。
Stay alert.
油断するな。
Of course. I won't let my guard
down for anyone.
もちろんだ。
どんなヤツにも手は抜かない。
紙分身か。
Paper Clones…
No matter how many clones there are,
いくら分身していようとも➡
蟲たちが すべてをくらいつくす。
our beetles will devour them all!
このにおい…。
This smell…
Get away, Shino!
離れろ シノ！
The Paper Clones were armed
with Paper Bombs from the start.
《最初から紙分身に起爆札を…》
本体には すでに
水が染み込ませてあるのか。
The real one was already
saturated with water.
自分の弱点を逆手にとった戦術。
She used her weakness to
gain an advantage.
強いぞ コイツは。
This one is strong.
You are that boy…
お前は確か…。
…from long ago.
あのときのガキ。
覚えていたようだな。
It seems you remember me.
知っているのですか？
You know him?
少しな。
A little…
何者です？
Who is he?
秩序を正す神だ。
A god who restores order.
どうやら正気ではなさそうだ。
It seems he's not in his right mind.
Naruto Uzumaki…
Where is the Nine-Tails?
うずまきナルト… 九尾はどこだ？
さあね。
Who knows…?
The hunt for the Jinchuriki is about over.
人柱力は ほぼ狩り終えた。
尾獣による忍び里のパワーバランスは➡
The Tailed Beasts are
no longer equalizers
in maintaining the power balance
between the ninja villages.
今や均衡を保ってはいない。
今更 九尾をかばったところで➡
It's meaningless to protect
the Nine-Tails now.
無意味だ。
やはり お前たちの狙いはナルトか。
So your target is Naruto, after all?
じきに争いが始まる。
The war will begin very soon.
戦争の火種は
あちこちに くすぶっている。
Seeds of war exist everywhere,
ready to explode.
And we shall control those wars.
そして 我々が
それらの戦争をコントロールする。
If you cooperate with us,
we would not be averse to helping you.
我々に協力すれば
助けてやるのもやぶさかではない。
この状況…。
From the state of this village…
我々の力も わかったはずだ。
You should know what
we are capable of.
Don’t underestimate the Five Kages!
五影を なめるな！
我々の先代たちが求め➡
You terrorists seek to destroy
the peace
our predecessors strived
to bring and maintain!
そして
維持しようと努めてきた安定を➡
崩そうとする お前らテロリストが➡
Your words fall on deaf ears!
何を言っても無意味だ。
Such arrogance!
驕るな！
Such chakra…
《なんて チャクラだ！》
This is the power of the Rinnegan?
《これが輪廻眼の力か。
今までのどれとも違う。
I've never seen anything like it.
イヤな感じがする！》
I have a bad feeling…
お前たちの平和が
我々への暴力なのだ。
Your peace has brought
violence upon us.
確かに かつて 木ノ葉隠れが
やってきたことが➡
I will admit that
some of the past actions of
the Hidden Leaf were not just.
すべて正しいとは言えない。
だが お前たちの
こんなやり方は許せない！
But your actions here
are unforgivable!
言葉に気をつけろ。
Be careful of what you say.
これは 神からの最後の警告だ。
ナルトの居場所を言え。
This is your final warning from a god.
Tell me where Naruto is.
言え！
Speak!
今 我々は持てる力の
すべてを注ぎ➡
We will pour every ounce of power
we have into bringing you down!
お前たちをたたく！
それだけのこと。
That is all I have to say!
それに お前は一つ
大きな勘違いをしている。
One other thing…
You have made a huge error!
What you desire, you shall never get!
お前が欲しがっているものは
手に入りはしない。
木ノ葉の忍が ナルトを
かばいきれると思っているなら➡
If you think the Hidden Leaf has what
it takes to protect Naruto, then…
それは…。
違う！
Wrong!
Naruto…is strong.
ナルトは… 強いぞ！
HIDDEN LEAF CIPHER DIVISION
(シズネ)ペインは６人。
一個体一系統の術しか使えない。
There are six Pains.
Each one can only use
one type of jutsu.
あの女は口寄せを使った。
That woman used Summoning Jutsu.
That means the Pain killed by Lord Jiraiya
was resurrected in a different body.
ということは
自来也様が倒した ペインが➡
別の体で復活したことになります。
(いのいち)そして間違いなく
あの女は死体として➡
And there’s no mistake…
that woman was transported to
Hidden Rain’s tower as a corpse.
雨隠れの塔に運び込まれていた。
Did that woman's corpse have
this imbedded in her?
その女は死体の時点で
これをつけていましたか？
いや つけていなかったはずだ。
No… I'm sure she didn't.
フカサク様も言っていたように➡
This proves that Lord Fukasaku
was right.
ペインに死者を生き返らせる
能力があるのは➡
Pain has the power to bring
the dead back to life.
これで間違いない。
それも 別の体で
いくらでも代用をきかせ➡
Furthermore, he is able to
substitute bodies as often as he wants,
and controls them by planting
these black chakra receivers.
この黒いチャクラ受信機を
体に埋め込んで行動させる。
(いの)それじゃ
あの６人のペインは…。
Then those six Pains are…
It's possible all of them are
actually dead bodies.
すべて死体だった
可能性があります。
そして 受信機があるなら
送信機もあるということ。
And if they have receivers,
they must also have transmitters.
つまり陰から あの死体を操る➡
So someone is in the shadows,
sending chakra signals and
manipulating them.
チャクラ信号を送信している者が
いるということか。
はい 自来也様が遺した暗号の
本物はいない というのは➡
Yes.
The coded message left behind
by Lord Jiraiya,
"The real one's not among them…”
６人のペインの中に
本体はいないという➡
Perhaps it meant that none of
the six Pains is the real Pain.
意味だったんじゃ
ないでしょうか？
そんな！ まだ別に
あんなのがいるってこと!?
What?! You mean there are
still others out there?!
Exactly.
(シズネ)そうなります。
《予測はしていた。
I did anticipate that possibility…
だけど いちばん考えたくない
予測が当たりだなんて…》
But as the worst-case scenario,
I really didn’t want it to be true.
それも相当な チャクラを持っている。
And that someone possesses
considerable chakra.
チャクラだけで これだけ自由に
遠隔操作するんだからな。
They are able to control this
many bodies remotely, this freely,
using just their chakra.
山中一族の転身系の術に
少し似てるが➡
It's similar to our, the Yamanaka clan’s,
Mind Transfer Jutsu.
But normally you can only
manipulate one person with chakra.
チャクラで他人を操るのは
１人が限界だ。
ヤツら ペインは６人もいるんだろ。
There are six Pains.
まだ陰に６人も
いるということか？
Does this mean there are
six others in the shadows?
それは わかりません。
We don't know that.
In any case, if this is
a Mind Transfer Jutsu,
(いの)どっちにしろ
転身系の術なら➡
he has to be pretty close to
the receiver in order to transmit chakra.
チャクラを送信するために
なるべく受信体の近くにいるはず。
Otherwise, it would be impossible to
pull off that magnitude of jutsu and attacks.
でないと あれだけの
術や動きは無理よ！
おそらく木ノ葉の近くに
潜んでいるはずですが➡
He must be hidden somewhere
close to the Leaf Village.
すぐに 綱手様に連絡して➡
We need to notify
Lady Tsunade immediately,
and organize a search party
to find the hidden Pain.
陰のペインの捜索隊を
編成したほうが…。
なに!?
What?!
How did we not notice him?!
《気づけなかっただと!?》
うかつに動くな。
Do not make a move…
この女が死ぬぞ。
or this woman will die.
クソッ！
Damn it!
妙木山。
Mount Myoboku…
父さんと同じ術！
The same jutsu that Father uses!
But he was able to search her mind
in seconds without any device?!
装置もないのに 数秒で頭の中を!?
どうやら ここには
ナルトはいないようだな。
It seems Naruto is not here.
妙木山。
なに!?
Mount Myoboku.
What?!
なに!?
ひいたのか？
They retreated?
どういうことだ？
What's going on?
Mount Myoboku…
妙木山…
たしかガマの隠れ里だったか。
That is the hidden village of the toads.
どうやら ここにいても
ムダなようだな。
Well then, lingering here is useless.
How did you know?
どうして それを…。
キサマ！
Why you…
綱手様 ここは いったん
コイツらを引かせて➡
Lady Tsunade…
We should let them retreat and
in the meantime, fortify the village.
その間に里の守りを
固めておくのです。
最後に１ついいか？
May I ask you one last question?
その足のチャクラ
俺の術に対応するためか。
That chakra in your legs…
Was it to counter my jutsu?
どうやら俺の能力は
知られてしまっているようだが➡
It seems you've realized my ability.
圧倒的な力の前では
すべてが無意味。
However, all is meaningless
before overwhelming power.
お前たち大国が
証明してきたことだ。
You great nations proved
that over the years.
お前たちは
この世界の主役だと思い上がり➡
You all think that you have
the leading roles in this world,
死を遠ざけて考える。
and do not think twice about death.
平和ボケして浅はかだ。
Soothed by peace, you become shallow.
人を殺せば人に殺される。
If you kill people, you shall be killed.
憎しみがこの２つを繋ぎ合わせる。
Hatred brings about
this cause and effect.
Quit babbling such nonsense.
戯れ言をペラペラと…。
In battle, both sides suffer death,
injury, and pain.
戦いとは双方に死を傷を
痛みを伴うものだ。
And we of the Great Nations
have had our share of pain!
私たち大国も痛みを受けてきた。
言いがかりをつけて
こんなことをするのは やめろ！
Stop finding excuses for your actions!
笑止。
That is laughable.
Lady Shizune!
シズネさん！
痛みを感じろ
痛みを考えろ。
Feel pain.
Contemplate pain.
痛みを受け取れ 痛みを知れ。
Accept pain. Know pain!
待て ペイン！
Wait, Pain!
痛みを受け取れ 痛みを知れ。
Accept pain. Know pain!
《まだ 何かするつもりか!?》
He’s still planning something?
痛みを知らぬ者に
本当の平和はわからん。
One who does not know pain cannot
possibly understand true peace!
大変でちゅ フカサクちゃま！
Bad news! Lord Fukasaku!
(フカサク)どうした？
What is wrong?
連絡役の コウスケ兄ちゃんが
やられまちた。
Big brother Kosuke, our messenger,
has been killed.
なんじゃって!?
What?!
名簿から 名前が
消えちゃったんでちゅ。
His name…
AMACHAN    GAMASPEED    GAMAKOSUKE
vanished from the register.
AMACHAN    GAMASPEED
ということは 木ノ葉の里に
なにかあったのか？
Does that mean something has
happened to the Leaf Village?
え!?
ナルトちゃん イヤな予感がする。
What?!
Naruto-boy, I have a bad feeling.
じいちゃん仙人 まさか
暁が 里に？
Geezer Sage…
Don't tell me the Akatsuki
attacked the village!
幸いにも
母ちゃんが食材の調達で➡
Luckily, Ma went to gather provisions
and is near the Leaf Village.
木ノ葉の近くに行っとる。
母ちゃんなら ワシらを含め➡
She will be capable of summoning
strong warriors, including us.
かなりの強者どもを
口寄せできるけん。
すぐに 準備せい。
Get ready now!
よし！
Right!
LEAF HOSPITAL
(サクラ)くぅ クソ！
Damn it…
これじゃ 全員は診られない！
I won’t get to all of them like this!
シズネさん！
Lady Shizune!
なに!?
What?!
(小南)どういうこと？
What's going on?
あれをやる。
え!?
I’m going to use that jutsu.
What?
どうやら 退いたようだな。
They seem to have retreated.
うん だが何か釈然とせぬ。
Yes… But it doesn't make sense.
シズネさん。
Lady Shizune…
においが完全に消えたな。
この辺りに ヤツはいねえ。
Their scents are completely gone.
They’re not around here.
ハッハッハッ 私の力に恐れをなして
逃げたようだね。
I guess my power scared them off!
《さすが 母ちゃん
父ちゃんのときと同じだぜ》
Leave it to Ma…
Just like that time with Pa.
どういうことでしょう？
ヤツらが ただ退いたとは。
What does this mean?
It’s hard to think they would just retreat.
《ペイン》
Pain…
((痛みを知らぬ者に
本当の平和はわからん))
One who does not know pain cannot
possibly understand true peace!
ヤツらは まだ何かをやる気だ。
They intend to do something…
何か？
何かは わからん。
Something?
I don't know. But it's something huge!
だが とにかく大規模なことだ。
(フカサク)頼んだけんの。
I'm counting on you!
母ちゃんに しっかり伝えてくれ。
はい。
Make sure Ma gets the message!
Yes, sir!
(綱手)カツユ 全員を守れ！
綱手様！
Katsuyu! Protect everyone!
Lady Tsunade!
《とんでもないことが起きる。
ナルトは まだか!?》
Something terrible is about to happen!
What is keeping Naruto?
早く知らせなきゃ！
I must get word to her immediately.
(シマ)あれは 木ノ葉の方向。
That's coming from the Leaf Village.
なんちゅうことじゃ。
Oh my goodness…
シマ様！
Lady Shima!
遠身水を通ってまいりました。
I came through
the distance teleporting pool.
フカサク様からシマ様に。
I have a message
from Lord Fukasaku.
口寄せじゃな。
To summon them, eh?
ペイン 何をするつもりだ！
Pain! What do you intend to do?!
ダメよ あの術は
あなたの命を縮めることになる。
You can't! That jutsu will shorten your life!
６人の力を…。
The power of the six is…
どうしてもやるのね 長門。
You’re really going to do this,
aren’t you, Nagato?
俺は弥彦の痛みを忘れない。
I will never forget Yahiko's pain.
ここより。
And now…
世界に痛みを。
This world shall know pain.
口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu!
神羅天征。
Almighty Push…
ゴホッ ゴホッ。
ゴホッ。
Wh-What is this?
何なのよ これ。
どうして こんな…。
How could this hap—
ナルト 早く来てよ。
Naruto… Hurry…
お願い ナルト！
Please, Naruto!
(ナツ)うっ… あ。
あ～！
気がついたっすねぇ！
There’s no need for the Leaf’s Hokage
to bother herself
with the likes of them.
ケツ!?
You just sit back and
sip some tea, Granny.
こらぁ！ ケツプリ団だ ケツプリ団！
お前ら なんの用だ！
I’ll take over from here.
おいおい ここが どこだか
わかってんのか？
Tell everyone in the village
to stay out of the way.
え？ な なんだここ？
It’ll be difficult to fight while
trying to cover for them.
牢屋だよ 牢屋。
兄ちゃん なにやらかしたんだ？
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
“Explosion! Sage Mode”
なにって… そうだ ルーシィ！
ルーシィは！
し 知らねえよ！
Let’s settle this!